# **Justin Casler**

Email: justinlcasler@gmail.com Phone: 617-981-2722 LinkedIn: linkedin.com Website: justincasler.com

Upcoming 2024 Computer Science and Physics graduate with a strong foundation in backend engineering and experience in object-oriented languages, database design, and data science. Quick to learn new technologies and excited to succeed as an intern software engineer.

### Education

Wesleyan University 2020-2024

Bachelor of Arts, Overall GPA: 3.85/4.00, 4x Deans List Award Recipient

Middletown, CT

Related Coursework: Introduction to Python | Artificial Intelligence | Computer Science I | Computer Science II | Multivariable Calculus | Vectors and Matrices | Quantum Mechanics II |

### Work Experience

Privacy Tech Lab

Middletown, CT

Software Engineer January 2022 to Present

> Wrote insightful, performant backend code for Google Research Scholar award-winning privacy product

- > Successfully trained NLP model to over 90% accuracy on test data set by creating and annotating datasets and specifying hyperparameters to optimize learning
- > Effectively debugged front and backend code quantified by high ratings in our usability study

Wesleyan University

Middletown, CT

Course Assistant September 2021 to May 2022

- > Assisted students in debugging code and forming methodologies to attack a variety of problems
- > Aided teacher by grading 25+ programming assignments per week
- > Held out-of-class help sessions to review concepts with ~20 students every week and received positive reviews at the end of semesters from students and instructor

## **Projects**

#### Pacman AI

Backend Developer September 2022 – Present

- > Wrote search algorithms (BFS, DFS, UCS, A\*) to create an Al agent that plays the game Pacman
- > Optimally selected algorithms to solve specific problems

#### Wesleyan Argus Crossword Mini

Backend Developer December 2021 – February 2022

- > Responsible for backend development of the Wesleyan Argus crossword webapp
- > Communicated with the Wesleyan Argus staff to fulfill their vision for the site

#### Skills

Programming Languages: Python Java JavaScript SQL C C++

Libraries & Frameworks: Node React jQuery TensorFlow PyTorch Pandas Hugging Face

#### **Interests**

Hiking, puzzles, cooking, and board games